https://www.manitoucamp.com/privacy-policy/

Privacy Policy
In order to meet the needs of our campers and have the ability to care for them we must collect personal information about them and their families and distribute some information to people who must care for your child, as staff or as a service provider. All of the information gathered is stored in our files which are secured in our locked offices and processed in a secure data base with appropriate access controls.
We do not sell or rent your family information to any company, organization or individual. Your contract allows us to distribute camper name and contact information only for mailing and communication purposes for other campers and staff. We do retain your information to enable us to communicate with you in the future, provide your camper with recognition for time spent at camp, provide you with information about our programs, do statistical analysis and inform you of new and exciting information that may be of interest to you.
Our Privacy Policy is here to help you understand the way we use the data that you share with us. It covers why we collect certain data, how we collect it and what exactly we collect. It also explains how and who we might share your data with and your rights regarding your data.
When we say “we”, “us”, “our” and “Manitou” we are referring to the five member director team who are operating the camp.
When we say “you”, “your”, “participant” and “customer” we are referring to either someone who has signed up for Camp or is visiting our website.
Camp Manitou Canada does not sell its customer data or mailing lists and will not share your Personal Data with any third party companies.
The Information We Collect
When dealing with our website there are three types of information we collect.
Personal Data
This is data that you voluntarily provide to us and is often information that we need in order for you to be able to learn about our program, or that may be given to us when you request more information and/or contact us.  It would also apply to staff who wish to learn more about the camp or apply.  It could also refer to alumni who wish to receive mailings and be in communication with us,  It is also data about you and your children and family that is relevant to provide them a safe and healthy summer and have communication and emergency contacts in place.
Usage Data
This helps us improve our websites and experiences and is often tracked automatically in the background such as your browser type, operating system or device type.
Cookie Data
Cookies are small packets of data which are stored on your computer or mobile device. Cookies are used to make certain features work on our websites as well providing reporting data.
Personal Data
Personal Data is any piece of data that identifies or can be reasonably used to identify you as an individual. We collect Personal Data in a few different ways with the most common being:
When you fill out a staff or camper application
When you request more information about one of our programs
When you register your interest in one of our programs;
When you contact us online;
When you voluntarily join our mailing lists;
When photos or videos are taken of your kids at camp.
When registering for any of our programs we will ask you for information such as your full name, email address, password, date of birth, address, postal code and country. During the application we will also ask you to voluntarily provide further information such as home address, emergency contact details, profile photo, work history and references and a host of other information.
When requesting more information about a program, registering your interest or contacting us online we may ask you for information such as your full name, email address and contact details.
Sensitive Personal Data
Information such as medical or criminal background, passport information and other personal details may be considered “Sensitive Personal Data”.
We use information you provide to us relating to a medical condition, disability or special needs you may have for the purposes of evaluating what suitable support may be available to you or your child and may be required, or whether you may be required to obtain additional insurance to participate in our program, and to share this information with our employees, camp employees who are directly involved in the application process or the provision of our services to your children or to you as staff.
We use information relating to any criminal conviction you may have for the purposes of evaluating your admission to our program, or for evaluating whether to allow you to continue on a program, and to share this information with camp employees and third parties for such purposes.
We collect passport information and your camp placement data in order to comply with the work permit requirements set by Citizenship and Immigration Canada and facilitate you or your child entering the country to attend camp.
This data will only be shared with a camp employer if you or a child of yours attends camp.
Lawful Basis for Processing Personal Data under GDPR
When registering for a Camp Manitou Canada program we will rely on a contract with staff and an application for parents for their child called “registration” as the lawful basis for processing your personal information. As a potential customer registering for a Camp Manitou Canada program we will need to process your data in order to provide you with our program services.
When signing up to marketing communications or providing us with feedback related to a Camp Manitou Canada program we will rely on Consentas the lawful basis for processing. You will be asked explicitly to provide us with consent for marketing communication at the point of registering for a Camp Manitou Canada program.
Lawful Basis for Processing – Criminal Data
Camp Manitou Canada has a lawful basis under Article 6 of GDPR (i.e., contract, legitimate interest) to process data about criminal convictions or offences; the company also has legal authority to do so under Article 10 of GDPR based on data subject consent. A comprehensive register of participant criminal convictions is not kept and any data related to criminal convictions or offences is anonymized when service is complete.
Usage Data
When visiting the Camp Manitou Canada website we collect usage data, which is done automatically in the background. This includes:
Device Information
Camp Manitou Canada collects information about the devices accessing our websites including: the type of device, device operating system, device settings, application IDs and unique device identifiers. The exact information we collect varies depending on device and system settings.
Log Data
When visiting our websites our servers automatically record information in server logs. These logs may include information such as your Internet Protocol address, browser type and settings, referring and exit pages, landing pages, pages viewed, language preferences and date and time stamps.
Location Information
When visiting our websites we will receive data that will help us approximate your location – this helps us deliver the correct language and website to you. We may use the IP address from your browser or device to determine approximate location.
Cookie Data
We use cookies on our websites. Cookies are files with small amounts of data, which may include an anonymous unique identifier. Cookies are sent to your browser from a website and stored on your computer’s hard drive. Like many sites, we use “cookies” to collect information, however the information is not personally identifiable. You can instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, if you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use certain features our website.
How We Use Your Information
We use the information we collect in the following ways:
To help you complete your application and aid you with your child’s summer experience or your own staff experience.
To respond to your inquiries and provide customer support;
Confirming and/or obtaining references on your behalf;
For billing, account management and other administrative tasks;
To send emails and other communications relating to service you have signed up for;
To send marketing communications;
To investigate security issues and prevent fraud.
How We Disclose Or Share Data
Camp Manitou Canada does not sell or rent Personal Data to unaffiliated third parties or companies for marketing purposes.
Service Providers
In order to provide our services to customers we use third party providers for areas such as infrastructure, web hosting, email communication, payment gateways and flight bookings.
Safety, Legal and Law Enforcement
Camp Manitou Canada may share your Personal Data in order to comply with safety, legal and law enforcement purposes.
Age Limitations
Our programs are for children but parents fill out all information for our campers- and we do not communicate with campers unless a parent has received the email.
Your Rights
You are entitled at any time to a copy of the information we hold about you and to correct any inaccuracies. Please make this request in writing via mail or email.
You have a right to ask in writing not to receive any direct marketing material from us, such emails or physical letters. You can amend your preferences in all of our email newsletters by clicking “unsubscribe”. Once notified we will take all the necessary steps to stop using your information for direct marketing.
Please write to:
Camp Manitou Inc
2478 Yonge street
Toronto
Canada
M4P2H5
or email:
mark@manitoucamp.com
Should you have any questions or concerns about our Privacy Policy we urge you to contact Mark Diamond, our Senior Director who is also our Privacy Officer at our offices. We will assume that you understand that we can collect, use, disclose as necessary and store information as set out in our Privacy Policy above. If you do not accept our Privacy Policy and decline to allow us to use your personal information or that of your camper, we may be unable to provide the care and services to make your child safe in our setting and we will need to discuss the status of your application for your camper this summer.
×
Take the First Step towards the Greatest Summer Ever!
Please e-mail us to book a virtual home visit.
We can’t wait to hear from you!
Winter Address
Camp Manitou
2478 Yonge Street
Toronto, Ontario
M4P 2H5
General Inquries: camp@manitoucamp.com
Phone: (416) 322-5888
Fax: (416) 322-3635
Summer Address
Camp Manitou
10 Camp Road
Parry Sound, Ontario
Canada
P2A 2W7
How would you like to start?
NOTE: All * fields are required.
Meet a Director
Request Information Package
Facility Rentals
Alumni
Meet a Director
Name *E-mail *Contact PhoneName of ChildAgeGenderPlease selectMaleFemaleGradePlease tell usPlease tell us about your son/daughter's interests and the length of session you are looking for.Comment or MessageHow did you hear about us?Please select ...Referred by a friendCamping publicationInternet Search EngineCamping WebsiteCamp FairAgencymysummercamps.comOtherPhoneSubmit
Request Information Package
Name *FirstLastE-mail *Contact PhoneStreet AddressCityProvince/StatePostal CodeCountrySelect you countryCanadaUnited StatesAndorraUnited Arab EmiratesAfghanistanAntigua and BarbudaAnguillaAlbaniaArmeniaNetherlands AntillesAngolaAntarcticaArgentinaOld style ArpanetAmerican SamoaAustriaAustraliaArubaAzerbaidjanBosnia-HerzegovinaBarbadosBangladeshBelgiumBurkina FasoBulgariaBahrainBurundiBeninBermudaBrunei DarussalamBoliviaBrazilBahamasBhutanBouvet IslandBotswanaBelarusBelizeCocos (Keeling) IslandsCentral African RepublicCongoSwitzerlandIvory Coast (Cote D'Ivoire)Cook IslandsChileCameroonChinaColombiaCommercialCosta RicaFormer CzechoslovakiaCubaCape VerdeChristmas IslandCyprusCzech RepublicGermanyDjiboutiDenmarkDominicaDominican RepublicAlgeriaEcuadorUSA EducationalEstoniaEgyptWestern SaharaEritreaSpainEthiopiaFinlandFijiFalkland IslandsMicronesiaFaroe IslandsFranceFrance (European Territory)GabonGreat BritainGrenadaGeorgiaFrench GuyanaGhanaGibraltarGreenlandGambiaGuineaUSA GovernmentGuadeloupe (French)Equatorial GuineaGreeceS. Georgia & S. Sandwich Isls.GuatemalaGuam (USA)Guinea BissauGuyanaHong KongHeard and McDonald IslandsHondurasCroatiaHaitiHungaryIndonesiaIrelandIsraelIndiaInternationalBritish Indian Ocean TerritoryIraqIranIcelandItalyJamaicaJordanJapanKenyaKyrgyzstanCambodiaKiribatiComorosSaint Kitts & Nevis AnguillaNorth KoreaSouth KoreaKuwaitCayman IslandsKazakhstanLaosLebanonSaint LuciaLiechtensteinSri LankaLiberiaLesothoLithuaniaLuxembourgLatviaLibyaMoroccoMonacoMoldaviaMadagascarMarshall IslandsUSA MilitaryMacedoniaMaliMyanmarMongoliaMacauNorthern Mariana IslandsMartinique (French)MauritaniaMontserratMaltaMauritiusMaldivesMalawiMexicoMalaysiaMozambiqueNamibiaNATO (this was purged in 1996 - see hq.nato.int)New Caledonia (French)NigerNetworkNorfolk IslandNigeriaNicaraguaNetherlandsNorwayNepalNauruNeutral ZoneNiueNew ZealandOmanNon-Profit Making Organisations (sic)PanamaPeruPolynesia (French)Papua New GuineaPhilippinesPakistanPolandSaint Pierre and MiquelonPitcairn IslandPuerto RicoPortugalPalauParaguayQatarReunion (French)RomaniaRussian FederationRwandaSaudi ArabiaSolomon IslandsSeychellesSudanSwedenSingaporeSaint HelenaSloveniaSvalbard and Jan Mayen IslandsSlovak RepublicSierra LeoneSan MarinoSenegalSomaliaSurinameSaint Tome (Sao Tome) and PrincipeFormer USSREl SalvadorSyriaSwazilandTurks and Caicos IslandsChadFrench Southern TerritoriesTogoThailandTadjikistanTokelauTurkmenistanTunisiaTongaEast TimorTurkeyTrinidad and TobagoTuvaluTaiwanTanzaniaUkraineUgandaUnited KingdomUSA Minor Outlying IslandsUruguayUzbekistanVatican City StateSaint Vincent & GrenadinesVenezuelaVirgin Islands (British)Virgin Islands (USA)VietnamVanuatuWallis and Futuna IslandsSamoaYemenMayotteYugoslaviaSouth AfricaZambiaZaireZimbabweName of ChildAgeGenderPlease selectMaleFemaleGradePlease tell usPlease tell us about your son/daughter's interests and the length of session you are looking for.Comment or MessageHow did you hear about us?Please select ...Referred by a friendCamping publicationInternet Search EngineCamping WebsiteCamp FairAgencymysummercamps.comOtherCommentSubmit
Facility Rentals
Name *FirstLastE-mail *Contact PhoneCompany/Organization (if applicable)Street AddressCityCityProvince/StatePostal CodeEvent InformationType of EventStart DateEnd DateAdditional InformationPhoneSubmit
Alumni Update Info
Name *FirstLastMaiden Name (if applicable)E-mail *Years as camper: Years as Staff:What activities did you work on or were your favourites? Tell us something special, funny or life changing about your time at Manitou: Contact PhoneStreet AddressCityProvince/StatePostal CodeCountrySelect you countryCanadaUnited StatesAndorraUnited Arab EmiratesAfghanistanAntigua and BarbudaAnguillaAlbaniaArmeniaNetherlands AntillesAngolaAntarcticaArgentinaOld style ArpanetAmerican SamoaAustriaAustraliaArubaAzerbaidjanBosnia-HerzegovinaBarbadosBangladeshBelgiumBurkina FasoBulgariaBahrainBurundiBeninBermudaBrunei DarussalamBoliviaBrazilBahamasBhutanBouvet IslandBotswanaBelarusBelizeCocos (Keeling) IslandsCentral African RepublicCongoSwitzerlandIvory Coast (Cote D'Ivoire)Cook IslandsChileCameroonChinaColombiaCommercialCosta RicaFormer CzechoslovakiaCubaCape VerdeChristmas IslandCyprusCzech RepublicGermanyDjiboutiDenmarkDominicaDominican RepublicAlgeriaEcuadorUSA EducationalEstoniaEgyptWestern SaharaEritreaSpainEthiopiaFinlandFijiFalkland IslandsMicronesiaFaroe IslandsFranceFrance (European Territory)GabonGreat BritainGrenadaGeorgiaFrench GuyanaGhanaGibraltarGreenlandGambiaGuineaUSA GovernmentGuadeloupe (French)Equatorial GuineaGreeceS. Georgia & S. Sandwich Isls.GuatemalaGuam (USA)Guinea BissauGuyanaHong KongHeard and McDonald IslandsHondurasCroatiaHaitiHungaryIndonesiaIrelandIsraelIndiaInternationalBritish Indian Ocean TerritoryIraqIranIcelandItalyJamaicaJordanJapanKenyaKyrgyzstanCambodiaKiribatiComorosSaint Kitts & Nevis AnguillaNorth KoreaSouth KoreaKuwaitCayman IslandsKazakhstanLaosLebanonSaint LuciaLiechtensteinSri LankaLiberiaLesothoLithuaniaLuxembourgLatviaLibyaMoroccoMonacoMoldaviaMadagascarMarshall IslandsUSA MilitaryMacedoniaMaliMyanmarMongoliaMacauNorthern Mariana IslandsMartinique (French)MauritaniaMontserratMaltaMauritiusMaldivesMalawiMexicoMalaysiaMozambiqueNamibiaNATO (this was purged in 1996 - see hq.nato.int)New Caledonia (French)NigerNetworkNorfolk IslandNigeriaNicaraguaNetherlandsNorwayNepalNauruNeutral ZoneNiueNew ZealandOmanNon-Profit Making Organisations (sic)PanamaPeruPolynesia (French)Papua New GuineaPhilippinesPakistanPolandSaint Pierre and MiquelonPitcairn IslandPuerto RicoPortugalPalauParaguayQatarReunion (French)RomaniaRussian FederationRwandaSaudi ArabiaSolomon IslandsSeychellesSudanSwedenSingaporeSaint HelenaSloveniaSvalbard and Jan Mayen IslandsSlovak RepublicSierra LeoneSan MarinoSenegalSomaliaSurinameSaint Tome (Sao Tome) and PrincipeFormer USSREl SalvadorSyriaSwazilandTurks and Caicos IslandsChadFrench Southern TerritoriesTogoThailandTadjikistanTokelauTurkmenistanTunisiaTongaEast TimorTurkeyTrinidad and TobagoTuvaluTaiwanTanzaniaUkraineUgandaUnited KingdomUSA Minor Outlying IslandsUruguayUzbekistanVatican City StateSaint Vincent & GrenadinesVenezuelaVirgin Islands (British)Virgin Islands (USA)VietnamVanuatuWallis and Futuna IslandsSamoaYemenMayotteYugoslaviaSouth AfricaZambiaZaireZimbabweCommentSubmit
Close
